Now, if you're having this problem and you tried everything now is your opportunity to try this new trick.
Take your foundation like so.
Apply it directly to the top and bottom lip.
Make sure that the color is very natural and close to your skin tone because what we're doing, we're creating a base to prevent the lip bleeding.
Once you do this, you're well on your way to stop the bleeding.
Once you secure your foundation on top of the lip like so, go ahead and take some translucent powder and apply it to the top of the powder of the foundation that you applied on your lip.
This is going to set your foundation.
Once you've done that, go ahead and apply your lip liner making sure to apply it right underneath the lip line.
This is going to help the feathering.
It's going to help your liner to stay on longer and when you apply your lipstick, it's going to also help your lipstick to stay on as well.
You can color it in a little bit with your pencil and this just kind of creates a base for your lipstick.
Once you've done that, you can go ahead and pick your lipstick color.
Once you pick your lipstick color, make sure that you use a brush because it helps that you don' t put on too much lipstick.
When you put on too much lipstick, it will run or bleed as your body temperature warms up.
So, once you've done this, believe me you would not have anymore feathering or bleeding of your lipstick.
Go back one more time.
Dot the lip line and the lip area withe the same foundation that you used.
Go over it one more time with your brush and reapply your lipstick.
If you do this, carefully you will have a beautiful lip.
My name is Sylvia Russell and this is how you can prevent your lipstick from bleeding.